Shakil Ahmed

Front-end Engineer

Dhaka, Bangladesh shakil.hv@gmail.com +8801709776055

Professional summary

Front-end focused software engineer with 3+ years of professional experience in the field fo web development. I own a proven track record in designing and implementing complex web applications. Collaborating in a team environment is a strength of mine as I possess excellent communication and problem-solving skills. One of my biggest strength is I can effectively push myself to achieve my goals.

Experience

Front-end Software Engineer, Brainstation-23 Ltd

Jan 2021 - Present

- Design and developed complex web user interface with clientside JavaScript frameworks (React, NextJS).
- Developed ChatGPT based desktop app with ElectronJS.
- Developed chrome extension which has 1000+ active installs.
- Wrote E2E test script and prepared CI/CD pipeline.
- Participated in each step of the product development process from ideation to development for features over 100k users.

Front-end Engineer, Hackverse

Mar 2020 - Dec 2020

- Migrated SPA to SSR which helped to gain 40% SEO performance boost.
- Developed PWA that increased significant mobile users.
- Wrote front-end for 3rd party APIs and SDK integrations.

Front-end Engineer Intern, Codeboxr

Jan 2018 - Mar 2018

- Build web application templates with HTML, CSS and ReactJS.
- Prepared technical documentation for front-end applications

Projects

Testfuel ⊘

- Test case management and QA automation system
- · Made with React, Redux-toolkit, TypeScript, Stripe

Shodai 🖉

- eCommerce grocery application
- Made with React, TailwindCSS, Ant Design, JWT

Boigram ?

- Online book marketplace.
- Technologies used are, Next.js TailwindCSS, Social Auth

<u>Upstarter</u> *⊘*

- Social site for startup community.
- Used React, TailwindCSS, Apollo, GraphQL

<u>MeetingSpace</u> ⊘

- SaaS for tracking and managing meeting in organization.
- Made with React, Redux, Material-UI

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, TailwindCSS, React, D3, Redux-tookit, Next, Express

REST, GraphQL, Microservices, CI/CD

Git, Figma, AWS, Docker

Communication, Leadership, Problem Solving

EDUCATION

BSc. in CSE

Daffodil International University 2017 - 2020

Certifications

- AWS Certified Solution
 Architect Associate
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Profiles

<u>GitHub</u> • <u>LinkedIn</u> • <u>Blog</u> • <u>Website</u>